Charles Coleman Sellers Collection ca.1940-1978 Mss.Ms.Coll.3
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles Willson Peale Portraits & Miniatures (Box 1-14)
  - Schaeffer, Frederick David, and his wife, Rosina Rosemiller
  - Screven, Mrs. Sarah Anne Proctor
  - Sculpture
    - American Art Journal
    - Anatomical models
    - Museum mountings
    - Wax: Lewis Meriwether
    - Wax figures
  - Selim
  - Sellers, Coleman, and Sophonisba Anguiscola Peale
  - Sellers, Nathan
  - Sellers, Mrs. Elizabeth Coleman
  - Sellman, Jonathan
  - Sergeant, Jonathan Dickinson
  - Sergeant, Mrs. Margaret Spencer
  - Sergeant, Thomas, and Henry
  - Sevier, John
  - Shewell, Mrs. Mary Shields
  - Shippen, Mrs.Edward
  - Shoemaker, Samuel (by Duché)
  - Shubrick, Jacob
  - Silhouettes
  - Silhouettes (Fake)
  - Silhouettes Gurney
  - Simond, Isaac
  - Singleton, John
  - Smallwood, William
  - Smith, Mrs. James, and Son
  - Smith, John (CWPeale? Charles Peale Polk?)
  - Smith, Jonathan Bayard
  - Smith, Richard H
  - Smith, Samuel
  - Smith, Mrs. Letitia van Deren
  - Smith, William, and grandson
  - Smith, William Thomas
  - Spear, William (artist?)
  - Spencer, Oliver
  - Sprigg, Mrs. Richard
  - Stagg, John, and wife
  - Stanley
  - Staughton, William (2 portraits by?? James Peale? A.C.Peale?)
  - Sterett, Samuel
  - Steuben
  - Stevens, Catherine Smith (C.W.Peale?)
  - Stevenson, Henry (C.W.Peale?)
  - Stevenson, William
  - Stewart, Charles
  - Stewart, Walter
  - Stoddert children
  - Stone, John Wilmer
  - Stone, Joshua Hoskins (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Stone, Thomas (Pine)
  - Stone, Thomas (minature: C.W.Peale or James Peale)
  - Stone, William
  - Stone, William Murray
  - Strachan, Mrs.William
  - Stuart, Gilbert
  - Sturman, Mrs. John
  - Sully, Thomas (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Summer, Andrew and wife, Mrs. Sybilla Peale
  - Sumpter, Thomas
  - Sutten, George, and wife Mrs. Rachel Bolitho
  - Sykes, James (A.C.Peale)
  - Symmes, John Cleves
  - Taney, Roger Brooke (Rembrandt Peale?)
  - Taylor, Bayard
  - Ten Eyck, Mrs.Susanna Barr Stewart
  - Ternant, Jean Baptiste de (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Thomas, Richard (by???)
  - Thompson, (Henderson)
  - Thompson, Mrs. John Wallace (James Peale)
  - Thompson, Mr. and Mrs. (by King)
  - Thomson, Charles
  - Tilghman (?) man and woman Davidson
  - Tilghman, Mrs. Anne Francis
  - Tilghman, Elizabeth, 1790
  - Tilghman, James (not C.W.Peale)
  - Tilghman, Richard, and wife
  - Tilghman, Richard (not C.W.Peale)
  - Tilghman, William (by Rembrandt and C.W.Peale)
  - Tompkins, Daniel D
  - Transparencies
    - Arch of Triumph, 1784
    - Arnold
    - Eidophusikon
    - Federal procession. James Wilson's Speech. Gray's Ferry. Columbian Mag. pp.391-400, 1788
    - Lafayette, 1824
    - Louisiana. Flag
    - New Years
    - Yorktown - Return of Washington, 1781
  - Trenchard, James
  - Truxton
  - Turner, Mrs. Sarah Wally, and son
  - Tyson, Hannah Yerkes
  - United States Magazine
  - Unknown
  - Unknown Corey?
  - Unknown Man - minature
  - Valette, Elie, family group
  - Van Berckel, Pieter Johan
  - Vanderhorst
  - Van Wyck, William, and wife, Mrs. Elizabeth Livingston Rowlins
  - Vaughan, John
  - Venus
  - Vespucci
  - Volney
  - Vose
  - Waggaman, Henry
  - Ward, Artemas
  - Warren, Joseph ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Washington, Bushrod
  - Washington, Mary Ball (Jones)
  - Washington, William
  - Waters,Richard
  - Waterton, Charles
  - Watkins, Nicholas J
  - Watmough, James Horation and wife Mrs. Anna Carmich (Rembrandt Peale)
  - Watts, David (?)
  - Wayne, Anthony
  - Wayne, Anthony (James Peale?)
  - Webb, Samuel B
  - Weems, Mrs. Mary Dorsey
  - Wendell, Evert, and wife
  - "Wesley"(?), John
  - West, Benjamin ( not C.W.Peale)
  - West, Francis
  - West, John
  - Wharton, Robert
  - Wharton, Thomas
  - Whetcroft, William (now at Yale)
  - White, B. A. (by?) and Mrs. Abraham White
    (by Joshua Johnson)
  - White, John (by James Peale) and wife Mrs. Rebecca White (by C.W.Peale)
  - White, Thomas (C.W.Peale?)
  - White, William
  - Wilkinson, James
  - Willcox, Thomas
  - Williams, Eli
  - Williams, Elizabeth Alston
  - Williams, Enion
  - Williams, Ephraim (by?)
  - Williams, Otho H
  - Williams, Robert Smith
  - Williamson, James
  - Willing, Mrs. Anne Shippen
  - Willing, Thomas
  - Wilmer, Simon
  - Wilson, Alexander
  - Wilson, Ann Stuart
  - Wilson, Margaret Custis
  - Winchester, William, and George
  - Wirt, William
  - Witherspoon, John
  - Woodford, William
  - Woodhouse, James
  - Worthington, Thomas
  - Wythe, George
  - Yarrow Mamout
  - Yates, Joseph ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Yeatman, Mrs. Angelica Charlotte Thompson
    ( not C.W.Peale)
  - Young, Mrs. James
  - Young, Thomas (no portrait)
  - Zantzinger, Mrs. Esther Barton
  - Zortan, Petratch
- Series. II. Mr. Peale's Museum (Box 15-20)
  - African
  - Albany museums. Peale's gallery, 1828.
  - American Philosophical Society
  - Amerind
  - Amerind - Correspondence
  - Anthropology
  - Arcade
  - Audubon, John James
  - Australian - New Zealand correspondence
  - Baltimore
  - Barnum - New York - Philadelphia
  - Barra Foundation
  - Biographies
  - Birds
  - Boston Museum
  - Bowen
  - Buckingham
  - Bullock
  - Chambers, Harmon A
  - Chemistry
  - Color
  - Colton, Harold
  - Collections - General
  - Dickeson
  - Drake, Daniel
  - Dunn, Nathan
  - Entomology
  - Exchange
  - Faxon
  - Gallery (American Pantheon), 1798
  - Grant expenses and reports
  - Guide
  - Harrington
  - Hawkins
  - Herpetology
  - Historical relics
  - Hutter
  - Illustrations
    Native American images note: 10 black and white gelatin silver prints, 3 photocopies, and 1 negative. (folders # 2, 4, 5)
  - Illustrations - Miscellaneous
  - Illustrations - Not used
    Native American images note: 23 black and white gelatin silver prints. (folders # 1-4)
  - Illustrations Peabody Museum
    Native American images note: 8 black and white gelatin silver prints. (folder # 1,2)
  - Indians
    Native American images note: 13 color illustrations, 4 photocopies. (folders #1,2)
  - Indians Red Pole and Blue Jacket
    Native American images note: 2 photocopies, 1 negative, 2 black and white silver gelatin prints, 1 color postcard. (folders # 2,3)
  - Jefferson Papers - L.C.
  - Johnson
  - Lamarck to C.W.Peale, 1796
  - Lever, Sir Ashton
  - Lewis and Clark
  - Library
  - Long Expedition
  - Kendall Whaling Museum
  - Labels
  - McGuigan, William
  - McNeil, Robert L, Jr.
  - Manufacturers
  - Mastodon skeleton
  - Mineralogy
  - Minutes, 1828-1835
  - Miscellaneous collections and museums
  - Mitchill, Samuel Latham
  - Museum Accession File
  - Museum - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellany
  - National Institute - Xeroxes
  - New Museum idea
  - New York
  - Nicholson papers
  - Oceania
  - Outlines
  - Palisot de Beauvois
  - Peabody Museum
    Native American images note: 28 black and white silver gelatin prints.
  - Peale, Franklin. Collections. Amerind, Swiss, etc.
  - Peale, Rubens - Memoranda
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay, Collection: fabrics, Samoa, Hawaii, etc.
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay, Collection: Pacific, etc.
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay. Manager's reports
  - Peale's Musuem
    - Correspondence A - Z
    - Burcher, Linda
    - Ewan, Joseph
    - Harvard University - Pea-body Museum
    - Lakari, David J
    - Sterling, Keir
  - Permissions
  - Philadelphia Museum Company
    - Accessions
    - Accounts
    - Charters
    - Descriptions
    - Failure
  - Preservations
  - Quadrupeds
  - Reading - Library
  - Richman, Irwin
  - Smithsonian Institution - Joseph Henry
  - Sornberger, Jewell David
    - Accession book,etc.
    - Boston Museum - Birds
    - Philadelphia notes, manuscript
    - Philadelphia notes, printed
    - "Walk..."
  - State House
  - Ticket
  - Utica
  - Wagner Free Institute of Science
  - Washington, George, relics
  - Wilkes collections
  - Wilkes expedition
  - Wilson, Alexander
- Series III. Benjamin Franklin in Portraiture (Box 21)
  All folders are marked: Franklin in Portraiture
  - American Philosophical Society
  - British Research
  - Childs Gallery
  - Correspondence
  - Filleul (Parsons)
  - History of project
  - New
  - Receipts
  - Yale-American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Washington Portraits (Box 22-23)
  These folders are marked as C.C.Sellers marked them originally.
  - Peale, Anna. Washington
  - Peale, C. W. Washington, 3 folders
  - Peale, Washington. Copies at Natchez, 1772
  - Peale, Washington. Edmund L. R. Smith, Washington and Lee: Historical Society of Penna., 1772
  - Peale, Washington. Diary, 1776
  - Peale, Washington minatures, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Herreshoff, 1776
  - Peale, Washington in France. Copies, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Miscellaneous correspondence: Antiques, etc., 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Lord James Butler, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Original. Brooklyn, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Prints (copied from Peale. George and Martha), 1776
  - Peale, Washington. (Samuel King?), 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Trumbull copy, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Amherst, 1779
    - Peale, Washington. Nordell Correspondence, 1776
  - Peale, Washington. Chastellux, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Metropolitan Museum of New York, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Miscellaneous, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Original, 1779
  - Peale, Washington, 1779 October 8
  - Peale, Washington French gentleman. D'Eschambault, Lejeune, etc., 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Oklahoma Art League, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Ortem Estates, London, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. St. Aubin, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Seligman. From France, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Shirley-Williamsburg, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. Versailles, 1779
  - Peale, Washington. (for B. Franklin) Neufville, 1780
  - Peale, Washington. Kirby-Yale, 1781
  - Peale, Washington, 1787
  - Peale, Washington. Mezzotint, 1787
  - Peale, Washington. (original) New York Historical Society, 1795
  - Peale, Washington, George
  - Peale, Washington, George (Balch, England)
  - Peale, Washington, (Blair)
  - Peale, Washington, (Cleveland)
  - Peale, Washington, Columbia Museum of Art, South Carolina)
  - Peale, Washington, copy by Samuel King (Robbins)
  - Peale, Washington, Dublin 3/4.
  - Peale, Washington, French gentleman correspondence
  - Peale, Washington, Goldsborough
  - Peale, Washington, (Huntington)
  - Peale, Washington, In Eisen
  - Peale, Washington, (McFaden)
  - Peale, Washington, minatures
  - Peale, Washington, Miscellaneous, new
  - Peale, Washington, (Mount Vernon)
  - Peale, C. W. Washington, George (ordered by Virginia)
  - Peale, Washington, Peabody Institute
  - Peale, Washington, (Penet-Pliarne)
  - (Princeton)
  - Peale, Washington, profile
  - Peale, Washington, (Rochambeau)
  - Peale, C. W. Washington (Small)
  - Peale, Washington, and Nathanael Greene
  - Peale, Washington, (Wilson Museum, Princeton)
  - Peale, Washington, Martha
  - Peale, Washington, (Laurens
  - Peale, Washington, Minature
  - Peale, James. Washington, George (2)
  - Peale, Washington, (J.P.Polk?)
  - Peale, Washington, Minature
  - Peale, Washington, (Alsop)
  - Peale, Washington, (Da Ponte)
  - Peale, Washington, (Paca)
  - Peale, Washington, and his Generals at Yorktown
  - Peale, Washington, without ribbon. Metropolitan Museum
  - Peale, Raphaelle. Washington in uniform, 1795
  - Peale, Rembrandt. Washington. 1779-cum Stuart, 1795
  - Peale, 1795 type (2)
  - Peale, 1795 type (Decatur)
  - Peale, (after Stuart)
  - Peale, Washington and Diogenes
  - Peale, Washington Apotheosis., Feb. 1800
  - Peale, Washington at Yorktown
  - Peale, Washington - drawing
  - Peale, Washington equestrian. Mount Vernon & Annapolis
  - Peale, Washington Hamlin 1795 type
  - Peale, Washington (Honolulu)
  - Peale, Washington later
  - Peale, Washington lecture
  - Peale, Washington (Lucas)
  - Peale, Washington (Lyndhurst)
  - Peale, Washington "Military, in two colors"
  - Peale, Washington Peabody - 1795 type after C.W.Peale
  - Peale, Washington (Porthole) Cofer
  - Peale, Washington Daniel Fox
  - Peale, (by C.W.P.)
  - Peale, Washington (Sturtz)
  - Peale, Washington (Tilghman-Lockwood)
  - Peale, Washington type
  - Peale, (West Chester)
    See also C. P. Polk (Goodell)
  - Peale, portraits
  - Peale, Washington, Martha
  - Polk, C. P. Washington
  - Polk, Washington (Donohue), 1788
  - Polk, Washington after 1795 type
  - Polk, Washington (Elgin Academy)
  - Polk, Washington (Straus)
  - Polk, Washington (Swift-Patten)
  - Washington at Fort Cumberland (James Peale? Klemmelmyer?)
  - Washington bust (R. Gilmor?)
  - Washington - Miscellany
  - Washington - Prints
  - Washington, Martha by???
- Series V. Paintings by the Peales (Box 24-31)
  - Archer, John, by??
  - Beatty, Ekurius by CWP???
  - Bowers, Mrs. Dorothy. Young Clergyman.
  - Chambers, Mary??
  - Cohen, Jacobs by CWP??
  - Cone, Spencer?
  - Davidge, Francis Hathorn
  - Den, Deborah?
  - Egleston, portraits, by???
  - Erlacker, Heins. Peale min. A.C.Peale
  - Ewing, Phebe, b., 1746
  - Fakes
  - Ferguson, Ebenezer
  - Foxall, Henry. not CWP.
  - Frazer, William Clark
  - Gardner, Charles K by??
  - Grundill, Mary Ann, by??
  - Hall, Charles, by??
  - Hall, John
  - Harrison, Anne, not C.W.Peale
  - Harrison, Collis. Polk?
  - Henderson, Thomas (C.W.Peale?)
  - Howe, Richard
  - Hughes, Charles. Watercolor. Peale?
  - Hutchinson, Mahlon
  - Imlay, John
  - Jewell, Kenneth Raphael? Rembrandt?
  - Johns, George
  - Kite, Isaac
  - Krips, Jacob
  - Leaming, Mrs.
  - Lee & Putnam - Engravings
  - Lincoln, Benjamin. C.W.Peale?
  - McCarty, Sarah Mason. Not C.W.Peale.
  - McCorkel, James
  - Marshall, Lucy C.W.Peale?
  - Maryland Historical Society. Peale Exhibition
  - Meacum, (Trump) C.W.Peale?
  - Miscellaneous prints, etc.
  - Montresor &c.
  - Montresor &c. Soldier, ship and fort
  - Murphy, Thomas Not C. W. Peale
  - Not Peale
  - Not Peale British officer
  - Not Peale Child (Glaser)
  - Not Peale "Rachel Jackson?"
  - Not Peale "Virginia Polk"
  - Parker, Daniel
  - Parker, Josiah. Miniature
  - Peale, Anna Claypoole
    - Biography
    - Coleman Brien and wife
    - Copied from other sources
    - Mrs. Samuel Hoffman
    - Man
    - Mrs. J. J. Nicholson
    - by James Peale: also, (self-portrait?) Minature
    - Self portrait
    - Mr. and Mrs. James Peale
    - Ellen Henrietta Phelps
    - Mrs. Samuel Poultney
    - (Dr. James Staughton) Key, John Ross - sketch by Rembrant Peale
    - Mrs. Julia Rush Williams
    - Mrs. Mifflin Wistar
  - Peale, Harriet Cany
  - Peale, James (painted by a daughter)
  - Peale, James
    - Allegory
    - John Ansley, 1801
    - Josiah Hewes Anthony (minature)
    - Miss Bakewell
    - Battle of Princeton
    - Sebastian Baumann
    - Paul Beck, Jr.
    - Biography
    - Elizabeth Patterson Bonaparte
    - James Canby and wife Elizabeth Roberts Canby
    - William Cobbett
    - Joshua Coit
    - Leonard Covington
    - Moses Cox. Middendorf
    - Thomas Humphrey Cushing
    - Ebenezer Denny
    - Reuben Etting and Frances Gratz Etting
    - Fort Moultrie
    - Elizabeth Foulke
    - Fruit
    - Mrs. A. Gamble
    - Horatio Gates
    - Hester Craig Green
    - William Haines and wife [David Haines?]
    - Alexander Hamilton (minature)
    - Dr. and Mrs. Harris
    - Nicholas Harwood
    - Mrs. Hay
    - Anne Howard
    - Mrs. Hunter
    - Mr. and Mrs. Blaighwaite Jones
    - Mr. and Mrs. Gibb Jones
    - Lady (minature)
    - Lady (Tolman)
    - Landscape (3)
    - Meriwether Lewis
    - Robert Lewis
    - Benjamin Lincoln
    - Herman Joseph Lombaert
    - Allen McLane and the British Dragoons
    - Louis McLane
    - Man (2)
    - Man and lady. Mrs. Montgomery
    - Marbury, William
    - Mr. and Mrs. John Mark
    - Lucy Marshall
    - William Mercer: Battle of Princeton
    - Minature (2)
    - Miscellany
    - Andrew Moore
    - Old Gallery
    - John and Olivia Morris
    - Roger Nelson
    - Lewis Nicola
    - Paul Oliver
    - On making Prussian Blue: Washing old paintings
    - Peter Osborne
    - Mary Britton Palmer and Ann Britton Cook
    - D. A. Parker
    - Anna Claypoole Peale
    - Mrs. Elizabeth De Peyster Peale
    - Jane and James Peale, Jr.
    - Jane Ramsay Peale
    - Margaretta Angelica Peale
    - Margaretta and Sarah Peale
    - Pleasure party at the mill
    - Mr. and Mrs. Zachariah Poulson
    - Susan Coren Powers
    - Ramsay-Polk Family Group
    - John Henry Remsen
    - George Richards
    - Thomas Robinson
    - Romantic
    - John Ross
    - Catherine S. Shober
    - Mary Jane and Edgar Simes
    - Pontius Delave Stelle
    - Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Summers
    - Washington Gardner Taylor
    - Chew Thomas
    - Col. Richard Thomas
    - Thompson, Mrs. John [UNK]
      (See Series 1)
    - Mr. and Mrs. James Trimble
    - and Francis Hopkinson. The Varied landscape
    - Vegetables
    - Abraham Bedford Venable
    - Thomas Walker
    - James Patriot Wilson
    - William Young
  - Peale, James, Jr.
  - Peale, Margaretta
    - Angelica
    - Angelica James Peale
  - Peale, Mary Jane
  - Peale, Mary Jane
    - Alice Burt
    - Negro woman
    - Self portrait
    - Portrait of a child (C.W.Peale)
  - Peale, Michael Angelo
  - Peale, Raphaelle
    - Biographical
    - After the bath
    - B, J
    - Berrett, Robert, and wife
    - Bogart, James., 1792
    - Betsy Bond (by Raphaelle?). Minature
    - Catalogue
    - A deception
    - Eagle
    - Ellicott, Andrew
    - Fruit (2)
    - Gibson, John. Minature
    - Godwin, Anne Gray. Minature
    - Heerman, Ralph
    - Jones, Absalom
    - Lady
    - Latrobe, B.H.
    - Lewis
    - Miscellany
    - Moore, Henry
    - Oliphant, Robert
    - Orange and book
    - Peaches
    - Peale, Mrs. Raphaelle
    - Peale, Rubens
    - Peale, Titian Ramsay I
    - Peale, Titian Ramsay II
    - Physick, Philip
    - Seecamp, Mrs. Mary Kimmel
    - Sprigg, Samuel, and wife
    - Two children. Watermelon
  - Peale, Rembrandt, 5 boxes
    - Apotheosis of Washington
    - (This is the (read) Rembrandt. - Rembrandt van Rijn 1606-1669 Folder [UNK] to No. 6)
    - Appold, Mrs. George
    - Arnold, Elizabeth R
    - Bates, Barnabas
    - Berrien
    - Biography
    - Blacksmith shop
    - Bloomfield, Robert
    - Boerstler, Christian
    - Boorman, Robert H
    - Boudinot, Elias
    - Burd, Edward Shippen
    - John C. Calhoun
    - Candlelight
    - Carroll, Bishop Charles (?)
    - Carroll, Charles, of Carrolltown
    - Children, from Corregio
    - Clark, Gerardus
    - Clark, John
    - Classical group (Wiltshire)
    - Clay, Henry
    - Cooke, Mrs. T. J
    - Corner, Solomon
    - Court of Death
    - Cox
    - Crayon
    - Crim sale
    - "Daughter"
    - Dearborn, Benjamin
    - Dennison, Elizabeth Brown
    - Dickason's book
    - Dixon (Katherine Douglas, or, Eliza). Minature
    - Du Comb, Rose Ribaud
    - Du Pont (de Nemours), Pierre Samuel
    - Duval, James S., and wife
    - Ecclesiastes
    - Ecstasy, after Greuze
    - Fancy head (R. D. Schwartz)
    - Fancy pieces
    - Peale, Rembrandt.?? (Ferguson)
    - Fiske, Elmira
    - Fitzhugh, George
    - Freeman, William H
    - Frick, Peter
    - Gaither, Henry C
    - Galaher, Rembrandt
    - Gallatin, Albert
    - Geoffroy Saint Hilaire, Etienne
    - Gilbert, William
    - Gillon, Alexander??
    - Godefroy, Max
    - Godman, John Davidson (Angelica Peale?, daughter of Rembrandt)
    - Guyton de Morveau
    - Hall, John Bishop
    - Harmer, John
    - Harrison, William H
    - Harrold, Alfred
    - Harryman, George, and wife
    - Hughes, Mrs. Thomas William
    - Haughey, Richard
    - Henry, Patrick
    - Hone, Philip
    - Hornor, Mrs. Charles Lancaster
    - Hosack, David (Sully)
    - Houdon, Jean Antoine
    - Hull, David
    - Humboldt, Alexander von
    - Hunt, Augusta
    - Jackson, Andrew
    - Jefferson, Thomas
    - Jefferson, Thomas (Greve)
    - Jefferson, Thomas (Manufacturers Trust Company)
    - Jefferson, Thomas
    - Jones, Senator George??
    - Kirkbride, Richard (Raphaelle??)
    - Koch, Jacob Gerard, and wife, Jane Griffith Koch
    - Lady in a lace hat
    - Landscape (Niagara Falls)
    - Lee, Thomas Jefferson
    - Madonna, after Murillo
    - Man
    - Man (minature)
    - Miscellany
    - Lafayette
    - Latrobe, Benjamin Henry
    - Legaré, Hugh Swinton
    - Lewis, Joseph Saunders??
    - Lukens, Mrs., and daughter
    - MacDougal, Peter
    - McKim, Isaac
    - McPherson, Mrs. John
    - Magarge, Charles
    - Marbury, William
    - Markoe, Peter
    - Matlack, Timothy
    - Meer, John
    - Miller, John
    - Moore, Thomas Lloyd
    - Morton
    - New York Lawyer (Levy)
    - Nicholas, Samuel
    - Nolan portraits
    - Old master copies
    - Patterson, Robert
    - Peale, Benjamin Franklin
    - Peale, Eleanor Short
    - Peale, Harriet Cany
    - Peers, Benjamin Orr, and wife, Eleanor Orr Peers
    - Powers boys
    - Pratt, Charlotte
    - Raborg, William
    - Reed, Franklin
    - Robinson, Henry
    - Robinson, Dr. and Mrs. Lewis
    - "Roman Daughter."
    - Roset, John Jacob and [UNK] Ann Laning Roset
    - Ross, John
    - Rush, William
    - St. Pierre, Bernardin de
    - Sayen, Ann
    - Schaeffer, Frederick Christian, and wife
    - Self-portraits
    - Sellers, Coleman
    - Sellers children
    - Seward, Louisa Cornelia
    - Short, William
    - Sibyl (Amies)
    - Smith, William Rudolph
    - Stratton, Nathan Leake
    - Stryker, Mr. and Mrs. Fenwick
    - Studies and sketches
    - Sumpter, Thomas
    - Thomson, John Paul
    - Three figures in a storm (Vose)
    - Tilden, Samuel Jones
    - Toby, Thomas
    - Townsend, Elisha?
    - Turner, Mrs. Joseph??
    - Twining, William Lee
    - Venable, Abraham Bedford
    - Warren, Mrs. Ann Turner
    - Warrington, Lewis
    - Washington
    - Washington and his portraits
    - Weeks, Samuel??
    - Wells, Charlotte Fowler
    - (Wereat, John?)
    - Wistar, Bartholomew
    - Woman's head (La Salle)
    - Wood, Mrs.
    - Wynkoop, Henry
    - Wilson, Mrs. Thomas
  - Peale, Rubens
    - Biography
    - Catalogue
    - List of pictures
    - Miscellaneous works
    - Old museum - Fruit
    - Partridge piece
    - Still life (Kennedy)
  - Peale, Mrs. Saint George
  - Peale, Sarah Miriam
    - Avery, Mr. and Mrs. Isaac
    - Bias, Mrs.James
    - Biography
    - Booth, Junius Brutus
    - Brunot, Louisa
    - Buchanan, Franklin
    - Calhoun, William
    - Carpenter, Mr. and Mrs. John
    - Carroll, Mrs. Charles Ridgely
    - Crane, Mrs. William
    - Easton, Mary Coffin
    - Fruit
    - Glenn, Susanna Butler Correy
    - Harryman, Mr. and Mrs. George
    - Johnson, Mrs. W &c.
    - Key, Louise Emily
    - Loud, Mr. and Mrs. Philologus
    - Man (Van Pelt)
    - Michel, Mr. and Mrs. Amadee
    - Miscellany
    - Montoya, Emily
    - Self portrait
    - Shorr family portraits
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay
    - iography
    - List of illustrations
    - Miscellany
    - Museum
  - Peale family
  - Peale family - Charles Clifford. Norman V. Peale
  - Peale family genealogy
  - Peale family - Angelica's descendants
  - Peale family, Anna Peale Amies
  - Peale family, R. D. Krueger
  - Peale family, Mrs. Grace Peale Martin
  - Peale family, James' descendants
  - Peale family, Geoffrey Plowden
  - Peale family, Raphaelle's descendants
  - Peale family, Raphaelle's descendants - Carr
  - Peale family, Raphaelle's descendants - Robert Peale
  - Peale family, Raphaelle's descendants - Rabold
  - Peale family, Rembrandt's descendants -
  - Peale family, Rembrandt's descendants - Godman
  - Peale family, Rembrandt's descendants - Peabody
  - Peale family, Ruben's descendants
  - Peale family, Samuel R. Peale
  - Peale family, Sybella Summers' descendants
  - Pickens, Andrew, by???
  - Pickering, Thomas
  - Polk, Charles Peale
    - Biography
    - Etting, Mrs. Elijah
    - Goodell, William N
    - Hack portraits
    - Jefferson, Thomas
    - Miscellany
  - Porter, John [C. W. Peale??]
  - Reed, Franklin